COVER LETTER

AMMAR HUSAIN

Contact: +91 9161642539; 9643260110 **Email:**<u>husainammar110@outlook.com</u>;

D.O.B: 4th November 1992

I am submitting herewith my resume for your perusal and consideration at your organization of repute.

Qualified MBA from University of Lucknow. Currently working with Xipe Tech as an HR – Officer since 25th January 2017.

Prior to Xipe Tech, I have also worked at JaZaa Financial Advisory Pvt. Ltd as an Analyst for 1.3 Years.

I am seeking a challenging job that would enhance my skills and knowledge with the objective of the organization. Being a dedicated and focused individual, I am determined to add value to the organization I work for and ready to take new challenges in life.

My basic objective is to hone skills for my comprehensive personality development and be an epitome of trust and reliability in the corporate world.

I will appreciate the chance to meet you in person to discuss as to how I could be a vital part of your organization.

Look forward for your reply.

Thanking you

Sincerely yours Ammar Husain

CURRICULUM VITAE

AMMAR HUSAIN

Contact No: - (+91) - 9161642539, 9643260110 Address: - 444/084 N Ali Colony, Thakurganj, Lucknow - 226003 Uttar Pradesh.

E-mail: - husainammar110@outlook.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To be associated with a dynamic organization that gives me ample opportunities to learn & apply my skills for organizational and personal growth.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Xipe Tech 25th Jan 2017 to Till Date Location: Lucknow, India.

Job Profile: HR – Officer Roles and responsibilities:

- Employee Recruitment and selection from Entry Level to Manager Levels.
- Training and Development of Employees.
- Ensuring legal and Statutory compliances of the company.
- Induction and On Boarding for new employees.
- Talent acquisition and reducing attrition rate of employees.
- Conducting Internal and External HR Audits.
- Conducting Organizational Health Survey (OHS)
- Conducting periodically performance review of employees.
- Preparing proper compensation system and reward structure for various levels.
- Understanding job requirements of the Organization and preparing job descriptions.
- Interviewing and screening the appropriate candidates.
- Finalizing the offer and rolling out the offer letter and appointment letters.
- Conducting Background Verification of the employees.
- Conducting exit interview and tenure feedback meetings.
- Employee engagement activities to make company environment lively.
- Improving ROI of HR Department and Implementing HR analytics.
- Preparation of KPI's and KRA's for various position in the organization.
- Coordinating with other HR Consultants for hiring needs.
- Working on Personality assessment tools to identify personality type of employees.
- Identifying training & development needs of employees and arranging for the same.
- Support current and future business needs through development, engagement, motivation, and preservation of the human capital.
- Develop and implement comprehensive staffing strategies that attract and retain talents.
- Issuing documents like increment letters, training letters, service letters etc. to employees.
- Ensure the effective maintenance of records and including insurance coverages, personal folders, etc.

- Keeping track record of employees' performance, conducting employee performance review for their increment and appraisal.
- Calculation of income tax of employees and deduction of TDS.
- Office Administration activities with management techniques like 5S, KAIZEN, MUDA, HENSENKAI, QUALITY CONTROL MANAGEMENT, QUALITY CIRCLES, JOB ROTATION, etc
- Preparing employee monthly salary and processing the payroll.
- Maintaining data bank of candidates.
- Hands on experience in walk in Interviews and Mass hiring

Project Coordinator Role at Xipe Tech in the Following Projects: -

- My Booking Box Live Project URL https://mybookingbox.com/
- Amazio Live Project URL https://www.amazio.com/
- Truzio Under Progress

Roles and Responsibilities

- Understanding project requirement with clients and meeting deadlines.
- Creating and closing and updating tickets on JIRA and ASANA
- Coordination of Development team with testing team for smooth deployment.
- Bug and attrition tracking in close coordination with the QA Team.
- Daily and weekly follow up meetings with client and team regarding project updates.

JaZaa Financial Advisory Pvt. Ltd. Location: New Delhi, India. Job Profile: Analyst Roles and responsibilities: 1st Oct 2015 to 15th Jan 2017

- Accounting reports and preparation of financial statements for audit purposes
- Financial planning and forecasting for budgetary decisions
- Analysis of business operation and preparation of (Cost and Expenses) reports
- Preparation of investment reports, risk and return analysis
- Capital budgeting decisions using techniques like (NPV, IRR, ARR, & Pay back)
- Liquidity & profitability decision using ratio analysis & profit and loss analysis
- Direct client interaction and client relationship management
- Market research analysis GAAP, 5 C's, SWOT, PEST, Poter's Model Analysis, PESTLE.
- Investment research analysis and preparation of investment cases
- Preparation financial forecasting reports including preparation of financial models.

SUMMER TRAINING AND DISSERTATION

Angel Broking and Financial Services Pvt. Ltd.2nd June 2014 to 28th July 2014 Location: Lucknow

Role: - Trainee

Project - Investment Behavior

- Analyze nature and Kind of investor in Indian Market.
- Analyze in which sphere an investor invest his wealth.
- Determine factors which motivate an investor to invest his wealth.
- Analyze Investor's behavior according to Indian Economic Conditions.
- Suggestions and advises to investor on wealth management.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded best performer of the year 2018 in HR- Dept at Xipe Tech.
- Awarded as best speaker in ISTD National Conference, Lucknow. (2018)
- Awarded as employee of the month at JaZaa Financials (Oct 2017)
- Awarded as best student with outstanding Grade in Tourism and Aviation Diploma.
- Won Certifications in Cultural Fests and debates at School, College level.

SKILL SET

- System Knowledge: MS Office, Paybooks, Quickbooks, On Time Attendance, Access Control System, JIRA, ASANA.
- Portal Knowledge: Naukri.com, Shine, Monster, Interviewfox, LinkedIn, Indeed, Times, etc.
- HR- Analytics, Talent acquisition, Recruitment & Selection, Onboarding, Training and Development, Performance Appraisal, Compensation structure, HR Audits.
- Analytical Ability and problem-solving skills.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

- MBA from Lucknow University (2015)
- Advance Diploma in Computer Applications.
- Diploma in Tourism and Aviation Management.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- Graduation in Commerce from Lucknow University (2013)
- Intermediate from La Martiniere College, Lucknow (2010)
- High School from La Martiniere College, Lucknow (2008)

PERSONAL DOSSIER

Father's Name Mr. Haider Husain **Date of Birth:** 04th November 1992

Nationality: Indian

Language Proficiency: English, Hindi and Urdu

Marital Status: Single

Address: 444/084 N Ali Colony, Lucknow – 226003.

Hobbies Learning Jurisprudence and polity.

DECLARAION

I Ammar Husain, hereby declare that information provided by me is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

(Ammar Husain)

REFERENCES: - (Available on Demand)